dentsuaegis.com 2019-11-06

# Privacy Policy | Dentsu Aegis Network

#### Privacy Notice 

Dentsu Aegis Network Global (referred to as “ **our”, “us”  **and  **“we”  **in this notice) is a global marketing network. We help our clients to improve how they advertise and market, whether by print, post, email or on websites. We believe that the responsible use of data supports business growth and builds strong relationships between brand and consumer. As a business, we are committed to respecting and protecting the privacy of all individuals with whom we interact. We are committed to being transparent in our handling and processing of personal data at all times in accordance with applicable privacy and data protection laws.

This Privacy Notice explains in detail the types of personal data we may collect about you when you interact with us on any website where this Privacy Notice appears. Dentsu Aegis Network is the data controller of any personal data you provide to us, including in relation to this website.

**This Privacy Notice explains the following:**

In the  **Supplementary Information**  section of this Privacy Notice, we explain what is meant by “ **personal data** ” and other terms used in this notice.

**1\. INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT**

The type of information we collect will depend on the circumstances and the service you are using. Generally speaking, we will collect information relating to you and/or your use of our services in the following ways:

**Information relating to your use of the website**

We and our third-party service providers use cookies and other tracking tools to automatically collect information about how you use our website. This includes information relating to the pages you visit on our website, the services or information you search for and the links and content you choose to access on our website. We may use this information to provide you with relevant content and to inform our marketing strategy. This type of activity is known as “profiling” – using automated means to process your personal data to analyse or predict your personal preferences, interest or behaviours. You may object to profiling (see Section 5 of this Notice, below)

**Technical data**

We and our third-party service providers automatically collect information about the device(s) you use to access our website. This includes collecting information about the type of device you are using, as well as unique mobile device ID or the internet protocol (IP) address online identifiers, which are numbers that can uniquely identify a specific computer or other network device on the internet. This information is linked to a cookie ID, which we receive and process. You may find more information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them on our [Cookie Notice](https://www.dentsuaegisnetwork.com/us/en/cookies-notice). We also collect information about your internet service provider and domain name and the type of browser and operating system you are using.  

**Contact data**

We collect contact details directly from you when you sign-up to receive email alerts, attend one of our events, download our content, subscribe to our newsletters or where you ask us to respond to a query you have. The personal data we collect may include your name, email address, employer and job title, and location.

**Marketing and communications preferences**

We collect information about your preferences in receiving marketing information from us and your communication preferences.

**2\. HOW WE USE THIS INFORMATION**

Except where required by law or court order, we use your personal data for the following purposes:

  * to deliver the specific information or services you have requested;
  * to enable the download of our content;
  * to send you newsletters and advertising messages (these may contain information relating to our brands and services);
  * respond to your requests and feedback; 
  * to analyse and/or improve our websites and services; and
  * to protect Dentsu Aegis Network, our websites, customers, employees, and business partners from fraud or other malicious activity.

In the table below we set out further information about the purposes for which we use your personal data and the legal basis we rely on for its use. Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful basis depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data.

  **Purpose/Activity**|  **Types of personal data that may be processed**|  **Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest**  
---|---|---  
To send you information about our services: · To send you information which you have requested e.g. newsletters or publications in accordance with your specified preferences| (a) Name (b) Email address (c) Company (d) General location| Where you have requested information from us, such as newsletters, publications or event invitations, we send such communications based on your consent. You can ask us to stop such communications at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the message.  
To improve and develop our website: · We conduct statistical analysis on your usage of the website e.g. to enable us to improve our website, offer new features and material etc.| (a) Technical (b) Usage| Necessary for our legitimate interest (to define types of clients for our services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy).  
To deliver relevant content to you, and measure or understand the effectiveness of the content we serve to you.| (a) Name (b) Email address (c) Company (d) General location (e) Usage (f) Marketing and communications  (g) Technical| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how clients use our service and engage with our content. To develop our service, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy).  
· To respond to any enquiries or feedback that you send us · To update you with any changes to our terms and conditions/other policies| (a) Name (b) Email address (c) Company (d) General location| It is in our legitimate interest to respond to communications that you send to us, inform you of relevant information in relation to the services that we provide and utilise your information to improve our business.  
To send you information on our products and services relevant to your needs| (a) Name (b) Email address (c) General Location (d) Usage| It is our legitimate interests to work out which of our products or services may interest you and tell you about them.  
To protect this website, our company, our employees, and our users from malicious attacks, hacking, fraud, or other illegal or unauthorized activity| (a) Name (b) Email address (c) General Location (d) Usage (e) Technical| It is our legitimate interests to investigate and take steps to prevent potential fraud or other wrongdoing.  
To share information with our service providers.| (a) Name (b) Email address (c) Usage (d) Marketing and communications (e) Technical| It is our legitimate business interest to share your data with trusted third parties who provide us with services relevant to the provision of our website.  
To share information within the Dentsu Aegis Network group.| (a) Name (b) Email address (c) Location (d) Usage| As Dentsu Aegis Network operates as a global operating media company, it is our legitimate business interest to share your data within the Dentsu Aegis Network group in order to manage our business effectively and provide our products and services.  
To share information with other third parties, such as regulator and law enforcement agencies| (a) Name (b) Email address (c) Location (d) Usage (e) Technical| We share your data as necessary for compliance with any legal obligation to which we are subject or in order to satisfy our legitimate business interests.  
  
**  
3\. INFORMATION SHARING AND DISCLOSURE**

_Information shared within the Dentsu Aegis Network_

The Dentsu Aegis Network is a globally operating media group consisting of multiple companies. Therefore, we may from time to time disclose your personal data within our group of companies.

_Information shared with our third-party service providers_

We use a number of third parties to perform business functions on our behalf, such as sending our newsletters and hosting our online services and customer relationship management. We will disclose personal data to these vendors and service providers to enable them to provide their services. 

_Information shared due to corporate mergers or restructuring_

We may disclose personal data with any successor to all or part of our business. For example, if part of our business is sold, we may give our customer list as part of that transaction. 

_Information shared with other parties as required by law or to prevent or investigate illegal activities_

Where required or permitted by law, personal data may be provided to others, such as regulator and law enforcement agencies, for example in response to a court order or a subpoena, or in response to a law enforcement agency’s request, or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, and as otherwise required by law.

We may share personal data as otherwise disclosed to you from time to time. 

We do not sell or rent any personal data about you to any third party.

**4\. INTERNATIONAL AND GROUP COMPANY TRANSFERS**

Dentsu Aegis Network is a globally operating media group consisting of multiple companies. Therefore, we may from time to time disclose your personal data within our group of companies. Some of our group companies are located outside the European Union (“EU”) or European Economic Area (“EEA”), but we implement and maintain policies designed to ensure the security of such disclosures and transfers in accordance with the applicable privacy and data protection laws.

If you reside in the EU or EEA, we will only transfer your personal data outside the EU or EEA where we are satisfied that adequate levels of protection are in place designed to protect the integrity and security of any information being processed in compliance with applicable privacy and data protection laws. These measures may include, as applicable, the use of standard contractual/data protection clauses adopted by the European Commission and where transfers are to the United States of America, the EU-US Privacy Shield, Swiss-US Privacy Shield or your consent. Where we transfer personal data between our group companies we have covered these transfers by entering into standard contractual clauses adopted by the European Commission. 

You may request further information on the measures used for such transfers via the contact details given in this Privacy Notice.

**5\. YOUR CHOICES**

You have certain choices about how we use your information. 

You can control cookies and tracking tools. To learn more about your choices related to cookies and our Do-Not-Track Policy, please see our [Cookie Notice](https://www.dentsuaegisnetwork.com/us/en/cookies-notice). 

You may choose not to receive marketing communications from us. You can ask us to stop such messages at any time by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the message. Please note that even if you choose not to receive marketing communications from us, you still may receive non-marketing communications, such as responses to your inquiries or notices regarding your account or our relationship with you.

**6\. YOUR EU/EEA RIGHTS**

Under EU data protection law we are required to advise you on the legal basis for processing your personal data. For the most part, the processing of your personal information is based either on a) our legitimate interests related to us providing you services you have requested or otherwise your customer relationship with us, or b) your consent, where requested. 

Where provided under applicable law, you may have the following rights: 

  * **Object to our processing  **of your personal data where we are relying on legitimate interest (or those of a third-party), and you want to object to processing on this ground, as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have a right to object where we are processing your personal data for the purposes of direct marketing or profiling. You can object at any time and we shall stop processing the information you have objected to, unless we can show compelling legitimate grounds to continue that processing.
  * **Access your personal data**. If you make this kind of request and we hold personal data about you. We are required to provide you with information on it, including a description and copy of the personal data and why we are processing it. We will require you to prove your identity before granting access to your personal data. We will process your request within the timeframe required under the relevant law.
  * **Request the transfer of your personal data**. We will provide to you or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Please note, this right applies to the personal data you have provided to us; and if we use your personal data on the basis of consent or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
  * **Request erasure (deletion) of your personal data**. You have a right to ask us to delete or remove your data where you have successfully exercised your right to object (see above), or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Please note, we may be required to retain certain information by law and/or for our own legitimate business purpose. But when we do so, we will inform you
  * **Request correction**  or updating of your personal data. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected.
  * **Request the restriction of our processing**  of your personal data in some situations. If you request this, we can continue to store your personal data but are restricted from processing it while the restriction is in place.
  * **Withdraw your consent.**  Where you have provided your consent to our processing of your personal data you can withdraw your consent at any time. If you do withdraw consent, that will not affect the lawfulness of what we have done with your personal data before you withdrew consent.
  * **Make a Complaint**. We will do our best to resolve any complaint. However, if you feel we have not resolved your complaint, you have a right to make a complaint to your local data protection authority. For example, in the UK, the local data protection authority is the UK Information Commissioner's Office.

If you exercise the rights above and there is any question about who you are, we may require you to provide information from which we can satisfy ourselves as to your identity.

**7\. OUR RESPONSIBILITY FOR WEBSITE LINKS**

This Privacy Notice is limited to the personal data collected by Dentsu Aegis Network. We do provide links within this site to other websites, including social media sites such as Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn. If you follow these links, your use of these sites will be governed by their applicable user and privacy notices since their data practices fall outside the scope of this Privacy Notice. Further, we can have no responsibility for or control over the information collected by any third-party website and we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you may provide on such websites.

**8\. UPDATES**

This Privacy Notice may be updated from time to time to reflect changes in law, best practice or a change in our practices regarding the treatment of personal data. The date of the most recent revision will appear at the top of this page. If you do not agree to the changes, please do not continue to use our services and please refrain from sharing your personal data with us. You should check this notice frequently for updates.

**9\. CHILDREN**

This website is not intended for children aged 16 or under. We do not actively seek to collect personal data about children aged 16 or under. If you have any concerns about your child’s privacy in relation to our services, or if you believe that your child under the age of 16 may have entered personal data onto our website, please contact us at dpo@dentsuaegis.com. We will delete such personal data from our records or seek verifiable parental or legal guardian consent to retain such information within a reasonable time.

**10\. CONTACT US**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice, our approach to privacy or you would like to exercise any of the rights mentioned in this Privacy Notice you can contact our Data Protection Officer in any of the following ways:

**Address** : Data Protection Officer, Dentsu Aegis Network, Regent’s Place, 10 Triton Street, London, NW1 3BF

**Telephone** : (+44) (0) 207 070 7700

**Email** : dpo@dentsuaegis.com

**SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION**

In this Supplementary Information section, we explain some of terminology used in this Privacy Notice.

**“data controller”  **– the person or company that controls the purposes and means of processing personal data.

" **personal data** " – any information that relates to you (or from which you can be identified).

**  “processing”** – means doing anything with data. For example, it includes collecting it, holding it, disclosing it and deleting it.

**“profiling”**  \- using automated means to process personal data in order to work out certain things about people, like analysing or predicting their performance at work, reliability, economic situation, personal preferences, interests, behaviour, location or movements.

" **transfer** " – sending personal information outside the European Economic Area (e.g. by storing it on equipment located outside the European Economic Area), or allowing someone from outside the European Economic Area to access the personal information.

**Cookie Notice**

Please read below for more information on the cookies we use, the purposes for which we use them, and how to reject cookies.

**How to reject cookies**

Our Do-Not-Track Policy: If you don’t want to receive cookies, you can alter your browser settings. The procedure for doing so varies from one browser application to another. If you wish to reject cookies from our site, but wish to accept those from other sites, you may choose the option in your browser settings to receive a notice before a cookie is stored on your device. If you block or reject cookies, not all of the tracking described below will stop. Please consult the “Help” section of your browser for more information. 

To find out more or to opt out of having your online behaviour collected for advertising purposes, please consult the following: [http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookiies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies) and [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) (for EU users) or http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN (for U.S. users). Choices you make are device-specific and browser-specific. By disabling cookies, you may be prevented from accessing some features of our site or certain content or functionality may not be available. 

**How we deploy “cookies”**

Cookies are small packets of information stored by your web browser when you visit certain websites, including our website. Cookies are generally used by websites to improve your user experience by enabling that website to ‘remember’ you, either strictly for the duration of your visit (using a “Session” cookie which is erased when you close your browser) or for repeat visits (using a “Permanent” cookie). 

**Our site uses the following types of cookies:**

**Strictly necessary cookies**

We deploy cookies to help us to identify how users navigate to and around our website and to enable some of the features within the site that may be beneficial to you (for example, language preferences, or print page features). This helps us deliver an effective online service to you. These are known as “First Party” cookies.

The strictly necessary cookies are listed below:

**Cookie Name**|  **Purpose**  
---|---  
__RequestVerificationToken| This is an anti-forgery cookie set by web applications built using ASP.NET MVC technologies. It is designed to stop unauthorised posting of content to a website, known as Cross-Site Request Forgery. It holds no information about the user and is destroyed on closing the browser.  
  
**Functionality Cookies**

These cookies allow our sites to remember choices you make (such as user name, or region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web page which you can customise. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.

The functionality cookies are listed below:

**Cookie Name**|  **Purpose**  
---|---  
language| This cookie is used to store language preferences, to serve up content in the stored language.  
  
**Performance cookies**

We may also use cookies issued by third parties (“Third Party” cookies) to track the websites you visited or search terms you used immediately prior to visiting this site, or to collect information about how visitors use the site. We use Google Analytics for this purpose. Google Analytics uses its own cookies. These cookies are not used to identify visitors. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. It is only used to improve how the site works. You can find out more about Google Analytics cookies here: https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies .

You can avoid the use of Google Analytics relating to your use of our site by downloading and installing the Browser Plugin available via this link: 

http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB.

The performance cookies are listed below:

**Cookie Name**|  **Purpose**  
---|---  
_gid| This cookie name is associated with Google Universal Analytics. This cookie stores and updates a unique value for each page visited.  
_pk_id*| This cookie name is associated with the Piwik open source web analytics platform. It is used to help website owners track visitor behaviour and measure site performance. It is a pattern type cookie, where the prefix _pk_id is followed by a short series of numbers and letters, which is believed to be a reference code for the domain setting the cookie.  
_gat| This cookie name is associated with Google Universal Analytics, according to documentation it is used to throttle the request rate - limiting the collection of data on high traffic sites. It expires after 10 minutes.  
_pk_ses*| This cookie name is associated with the Piwik open source web analytics platform. It is used to help website owners track visitor behaviour and measure site performance. It is a pattern type cookie, where the prefix _pk_ses is followed by a short series of numbers and letters, which is believed to be a reference code for the domain setting the cookie.  
_ga| This cookie name is associated with Google Universal Analytics - which is a significant update to Google's more commonly used analytics service. This cookie is used to distinguish unique users by assigning a randomly generated number as a client identifier. It is included in each page request in a site and used to calculate visitor, session and campaign data for the sites analytics reports. By default it is set to expire after 2 years, although this is customisable by website owners.  
JSESSIONID| This domain is third party performance cookie. It is controlled by New Relic, which provides a platform for monitoring the performance of web and mobile applications.  
  
These cookies are used when you share information using a social media sharing button or “like” button on our site or you link your account or engage with our content on or through a social networking site such as Facebook, Twitter or Google+. The social network will record that you have done this. This information may be linked to targeting/advertising activities.

The social media cookies are listed below:

**Cookie Name**|  **Purpose**  
---|---  
Google DoubleClick| We use these cookies to measure the effectiveness of our online marketing campaigns; to improve reporting on campaign performance; and to avoid showing ads the user has already seen.  
Google Analytics| These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our website. We use the information to help us improve the website. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the website, where visitors have come to the website from and the pages they visited.  
**Twitter** auth_token twll __utmz secure_session guest_id __utma remember_checked remember_checked_on| Twitter uses cookies and other similar technologies, such as pixels or local storage, to help provide you with a better, faster, and safer experience. Like many websites, Twitter uses cookies to discover how people are using their services and to make them work better.  
**YouTube** SID and HSID                 Demographics       VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE           PREF             APISID SSID LOGIN_INFO YSC SAPISID| YouTube is a Google owned platform for hosting and sharing videos. YouTube collects user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites. the HSID cookies is used by Google in combination with SID to verify Google user account and most recent login time.       This cookie is used for demographic profiling and targeting for advertising.     This cookie is used as a unique identifier to track viewing of videos.                 This is a common Google cookie, used across several of their services. Stores user preference, can be used to personalise ads on google searches.                 These cookies are used by YouTube to collect user data through videos embedded in websites, which is aggregated with profile data from other Google services in order to display targeted advertising to web visitors across a broad range of their own and other websites.
